Guide to the International Federation for Home Economics-United States records, 1975-2016.
International Federation for Home Economics-United States
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
International Federation for Home Economics-United States records, 1975-2016.
6760
International Federation for Home Economics-United States.
4.3 cubic feet
Correspondence, reports, minutes, conference proceedings, photographs, videotapes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, reports, and newsletters of IFHE-US; reports, proceedings, photographs, and other conference materials from IFHE Council meetings and Congresses. Records of the IFHE-US Development Fund.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The IFHE-US serves as the coordinating pivot for all US individual and organizational members of IFHE, including the American Association of Family and Consumer Sciences (AAFCS) and others, to promote the mission and work of IFHE.
In the 1996 at the IFHE Council and Congress in Bangkok, changes to constitution and by-laws were approved allowing changes in the over all structure. These changes gave additional emphasis to programming in the five IFHE regions and provided the number of votes per country giving representation to individual members for the first time. These changes required the formation of the US structure committee resulting in the IFHE-US organization being the representative of the US members of IFHE.
IFHE-US began in a structure meeting at Lake Jackson, Florida in January 1996 and the formal creation of IFHE-US was with a Memorandum of Understanding (MOU) with AAFCS effective in 1999. This was followed by the formal closing of the AAFCS/IFHE Liaison Committee in June 2000.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, reports, and newsletters of IFHE-US; reports, proceedings, photographs, and other conference materials from IFHE Council meetings and Congresses. Records of the IFHE-US Development Fund.
SUBJECTS
Names:
International Federation for Home Economics-United States.; American Association of Family and Consumer Sciences.; American Home Economics Association.; IFHE-US.; International Federation for Home Economics.; International Federation for Home Economics. Region of the Americas.
Subjects:
Home economics; Home economics--International cooperation.; International Year of the Family, 1994.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Videocassettes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
American Association of Family and Consumer Sciences records, #6578.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Governance and History
Series II. Councils, Congresses and Workshops
A. Bangkok, Thailand - Council and Congress
B. Sheffield, England - Council
C. International Home Economics and Consumer Studies Research Conference
D. Hanover, Germany - Council and Congress
E. Minneapolis, Minnesota - Congress
F. Mayaguez, Puerto Rico - Council
G. Region of the Americas Conference - Pre-Council Workshop
H. Commission on the Status of Women - Workshop
I. Accra, Ghana - Council and Congress
J. International Year of the Family
K. Helsinki, Finland - Council
L. Melbourne, Australia - World Congress
Series III. United States Development Fund
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Governance and History
  - History (Box 3)
  - IFHE reports and correspondence, 1975-1996 (Box 3)
  - AAFCS-IFHE Chicago celebration; IFHE Congress, Bangkok, Thailand, 1996, 2 VHS videotapes (Box 3)
  - IFHE-US history draft (Box 3)
  - IFHE-newsletters-"Home Economics News", 1997-2001 (Box 3)
  - IFHE-US newsletters, 1991, 1999-2008 (Box 3)
  - International Home Economics Services newsletter, 2001 (Box 3)
  - IFHE history (Box 3)
  - Vienna NGO Committee on the Family, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous IFHE materials (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, celebration at AAFCS, Chicago, 2000 (Box 3)
  - IFHE-US Liaison Committee, 1997-1999 (Box 3)
  - Structure meetings, 1999-2000 (Box 3)
  - Restructuring teleconference, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Materials for IFHE/IFHE-US from annual meeting, Seattle, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Working draft of IFHE-US history, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence and draft bylaws, 1999 (Box 3)
  - IFHE/AAFCS Liaison Structure Committee, 1998 (Box 3)
  - IFHE-US Structure Committee, 1997 (Box 3)
  - AAFCS/IFHE Liaison Committee and IFHE-US Restructuring Committee, 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - IFHE-US Structure Committee, 1996 (Box 3)
  - IFHE-US organizational meeting materials (Box 3)
  - Correspondence on IFHE, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - IFHE-US Structure Committee, January 1996 (Box 3)
  - IFHE-US Structure Committee, March 1996 (Box 3)
  - IFHE restructuring memo; IFHE Council minutes, 1994 (Box 3)
  - IFHE-US membership directory, 1995 (Box 3)
  - IFHE/UN Task Force, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence and minutes, 2001 (Box 3)
  - IFHE history (Box 3)
  - Region of the Americas meeting, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Presentation to United Nations to be delivered on September 12, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Handbook International Division, no date (Box 3)
  - Handbook for AHEA International Section Chairpersons and IFHE Member Organization Representatives, 1988 (Box 3)
  - "People and Practice: Issues for Home Economists", 1997 (Box 3)
  - International Activities Survey, 1997 (Box 3)
  - "An Exchange Between the Caribbean, South, Central, and North America"- IFHE Conference, 1998-07 (Box 3)
  - IFHE-US Board of Directors (1999-2008); AAFCS- International Division Officers (1998-2000), 1998-2013 (Box 3)
  - IFHE-Global Network Match Service, 2000 (Box 3)
  - "Defining the International Body of Knowledge for FCS"- AAFCS Conference, 2002 (Box 3)
  - AAFCS 10th Anniversary of the International Year of the Family, 2004 (Box 3)
  - IFHE Position Statement, 2008 (Box 3)
  - Photographs, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Bylaws, 2014 (Box 5)
  - Policies and Procedures Manual, 2016 (Box 5)
  - Board Members, 2012-2016 (Box 5)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 2012-06-2016-06 (Box 5)
  - Business Meeting Minutes, 2012-2016 (Box 5)
- Series II. Councils, Congresses, Workshops
  - A. Bangkok, Thailand - Council and Congress, 1996-07
    - Travel and study tour information from the Ohio State College of Human Ecology (Box 1)
    - Travel guide and brochures (Box 1)
    - Program for Thai Cultural Night (Box 1)
    - Invitations (Box 1)
    - Ephemera from Congress and travel (Box 1)
    - United States delegates to Council (Box 1)
    - Congress program and brochures (Box 1)
    - "Household Food Security: A Critical Concern for Home Economics," Dr. Leena M. Kirjavainen (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous handouts (Box 1)
    - Information from Guam Cooperative Extension Service (Box 1)
    - Council memoranda and reports (Box 1)
    - Thai food booklet (Box 1)
    - Directory of International Home Economics Researchers and Research Organizations (Box 1)
    - Home Economics in Thailand (Box 1)
    - Plenary programs (Box 1)
    - List of Participants (Box 1)
    - Proceedings (Box 1)
    - Official Program (Box 1)
    - Research Abstracts (Box 1)
    - Quality of Rural Women's Life for Empowerment Around Kodaikanal (Box 1)
    - The Environment and Community in Japan - Their Past, Present and Near Future (Box 1)
    - The Progress of Nations (UNICEF) (Box 1)
    - Photographs (Box 1)
    - Commemorative paperweight (Box 4)
  - B. Sheffield, England - Council, 1994-07
    - Delegate lists (Box 1)
    - Booklets on nutrition and home economics (Box 1)
    - Home Economics News-Scotland Branch (Box 1)
    - Program and reports (Box 1)
    - Tour information (Box 1)
    - Photographs (Box 1)
  - C. International Home Economics and Consumer Studies Research Conference, 1992-07
    - Agenda and handouts (Box 1)
    - Proceedings (Box 1)
  - D. Hanover, Germany - Council and Congress, 1992-07
    - Notes on Congress materials (Box 1)
    - Council minutes (Box 1)
    - Reports (Box 1)
    - Reports, resolutions and memoranda (Box 1)
    - Women and Families in Development Committee (Box 1)
    - Invitation program (Box 1)
    - Travel information and newspaper articles (Box 1)
    - Congress poster, button and invitations (Box 1)
    - Presentations (Box 1)
    - Program (Box 1)
    - Proceedings (Box 1)
    - Participant list (Box 1)
    - Research abstracts
    - Photographs and slides (Box 1)
    - Small dish with Congress symbol (Box 4)
  - E. Minneapolis, Minnesota- Congress, 1998-07
    - Correspondence; AHEA Action article on Congress (Box 1)
    - Treasurer's reports, correspondence (Box 1)
    - Report of Local Arrangements Committee (Box 1)
    - Official program, participant list and registration information (Box 1)
    - "The American Heartbeat", 2 VHS videotapes (Box 1)
    - Photographs (Box 1)
    - Resource Management: Environmental Issues for Home Economics [IFHE training program] (Box 1)
  - F. Mayaguez, Puerto Rico - Council, 1998-07
    - IFHE Council meeting, Mayaguez, Puerto Rico, 1998-07 (Box 1)
  - G. Region of the Americas Conference - Pre-Council, 1998-07
    - Official Proceedings (Box 1)
    - Proceedings (Box 2)
    - Pre-Conference information and correspondence (Box 2)
    - Brochures and newsletters (Box 2)
    - "A Critical Interpretation of Leadership for the New Millennium," Judy Annette Jax (Box 2)
    - Certificate of Recognition (Box 2)
  - H. Commission on the Status of Women - Workshop, 1998
    - Correspondence and conference information (Box 2)
    - Commission on Social Development (Box 2)
    - Publications and background information, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - I. Accura, Ghana - Council and Congress, 2000
    - Official Program (Box 2)
    - Participant list (Box 2)
    - Reports and presentations (Box 2)
    - Photographs (Box 2)
    - Articles (Box 2)
    - Home Science Association newsletter (Box 2)
    - Travel information (Box 2)
    - Ghana Home Economics Association cloth (Box 2)
    - Participant nametag (Box 2)
  - J. International Year of the Family, 1994
    - World NGO Forum, Malta: conference materials, reports, cassette audiotape, slides, 6 folders (Box 2)
    - NGO Committee on the Family (Box 2)
    - Convention on the Rights of the Child (Box 2)
    - Publications and newsletters (Box 2)
    - Presentations (Box 2)
    - AHEA activities (Box 2)
    - Conference on the IYF, New York State HEA, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Ohio Home Economics Association (Box 2)
    - Families in Transition (Box 2)
    - Publications, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Publications, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - K. Helsinki, Finland - Council, 2002-07
    - Photographs (Box 3)
    - Program (Box 3)
    - Report to OAFCS on Council (Box 3)
    - Travel information (Box 3)
    - Invitation to 2002 Congress, Kyoto, Japan (Box 3)
    - Invitation to 2012 Congress, Sydney, Australia (Box 3)
    - Reports, minutes and correspondence (Box 3)
  - L. Melbourne, Australia - World Congress, 2002-07
    - Tote bag (Box 4)
- Series III. United States Development Fund
  - Agenda, 2002-06-22 (Box 5)
  - Minutes, 2002-06-22 (Box 5)
  - 1994 International Year of the Family impact, 2001-11-24 (Box 5)
  - Letter about June 22 meeting, 2002-02 (Box 5)
  - Communications for June 22 meeting, 2002 (Box 5)
  - Vanguard Investment and Investment Subcommittee, 2000-2002; [29 folders] (Box 5)
  - Administration and Implementation of Fund, 1997-2001; [10 folders] (Box 5)
  - Policies and Management, 1996-2002; [5 folders] (Box 5)
  - Financial Reports, 1997-2001; [7 folders] (Box 5)
  - Adams Account, 1997-2000; [3 folders] (Box 5)
  - Contribution and Thank You Letters, 1997-2002; [4 folders] (Box 5)
  - Membership Committee, 1996-2001; [21 folders] (Box 5)
  - Annual Reports, 1998-2002; [10 folders] (Box 5)
  - Plan of Action, 1996-2004; [9 folders] (Box 5)
  - Articles, 1998-2001; [10 folders] (Box 5)
  - Agendas, 1997-2001; [6 folders] (Box 5)
  - Minutes, 1997-2001; [4 folders] (Box 5)
  - Fundraising Given Years, 1998-2007; [12 folders] (Box 5)
  - Money Issues, 1998-1999; [4 folders] (Box 5)
  - Reports to IFHE, 2000-2002; [5 folders] (Box 5)
  - Procedures/Operation, [9 folders] (Box 5)
  - Policies, [4 folders] (Box 5)
  - Tax exempt 501 information, 1999-2004 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1099 forms, 2005-2009 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Fund Annual Reports, 2001-2016 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Fundraiser - bookmark, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Fundraiser - notecards, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Fundraiser - Quilt, 2004-2008 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Fundraiser event - San Diego, California, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Fundraiser event - Minneapolis, Minnesota, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Fundraiser event - Charlotte, North Carolina, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Fundraiser event - Reno, Nevada, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Fundraiser event - Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Fundraiser event - Knoxville, Tennessee, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Fundraiser event - Cleveland, Ohio, 2010 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Fundraiser event - Phoenix, Arizona, 2011 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Fundraiser event - Indianapolis, Indiana, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Fundraiser event - Houston, Texas, 2013 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Fundraiser event - St. Louis, Missouri, 2014 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Fundraiser event - Jacksonville, Florida, 2015 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Fundraiser event - Bellevue, Washington, 2016 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Committee agendas, 2004-2016 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Fund committee member memos, 2001-2007 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Fund committee minutes, 2004-2016 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Fund contributors, 1998-2015 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Global Legacy Society, no date (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Grant procedures, 2014-2016 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Grants, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Grants, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Grants, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Grants, 2016 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Grant proposal forms, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Fund history, 1997-2015 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Investment management subcommittee, 2002-2008 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Finance reports, 2005-2016 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Macatawa bank statements - Holland, Michigan, 2004-2016 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Policies and procedures manual, 2006-2016 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Request letters, 2003-2014 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Financial reviews, 2005-2015 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Members of the board, 2005-2014 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - History draft, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Memorandum of Understanding, 1998-2012 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Newsletters - Connection, 1998-2015-10 (Box 6, Folder 41)